Domain 10 Application Security Questions 

1-What models exist for implementing a SSDLC ? 
Building Security In Maturity Model -  BSIMM2 / Software Assurance Maturity Model – SAMM / Systems Security Engineering Capability Maturity Model – SSE-CMM

2-What is SSDLC and SDLC? 
Secure Software Development Lifecycle / Software Development Life Cycle

3-What are differences in developing software in a traditional hosting environment vs. developing for a cloud environment? 
Control of physical security is substantially reduced in public cloud scenarios
Potential Incompatibility between vendors when services are migrated from one vendor to another
Protection of data through the lifecycle - including transit, processing, and storage
Combinations of web services in the cloud environment can potentially cause security vulnerabilities
Ability to access logs especially in a shared public cloud is difficult, should be specified as part of SLA
Fail-over for data and security in the cloud has to be more detailed and layered than traditional envir.
Assuring compliance to relevant industry and government regs. is more difficult in a cloud envir.

4-What principles should be followed in order to develop a secure design for the application?
Least Privilege, Segregation of duties, Defense in Depth, Fail Safe, Economy of Mechanism, Complete Mediation, Open Design, Least Common Mechanism, Weakest Link

5-What is dynamic code analysis?
Dynamic code analysis examines the code as it executes in a running cloud application, with the tester tracing the external interfaces in the source code to the corresponding interactions in the executing code, so that any vulnerabilities or anomalies that arise in the executing interfaces are simultaneously located in the source code, where they can then be fixed 

6-What are the three phases of a penetration test?
Preparation – formal contract, nda, legal protection, ip addresses to be tested
Execution – the test is executed with the tester looking for potential vulnarbilites
Deliver – results and evaluation are sent to the the org, corrective action advised

7-What’s the point of a interoperability testing?
Evaluates whether a cloud application can exchange data (interoperate) with other components or applications. It’s used to detect interoperability problems between cloud software applications before these application are put into operation. The majority of the application must be complete before this type of test.

8-Why should identity, entitlement, and access management be given special attention?
It impacts the customer in that integration is constrained by the credential passing mechanism. Billing and metering that depend on identity management also present integration and migration risks. Implications include securely passing credentials and attributes, provisioning additional users, etc. IdEA capabilities such as an applications ability to accept SAML assertion will impact the cloud service governance, integration, user experience. 

9-What terms are for when a user moves applications to the cloud and all traditional controls like firewalls, proxies, trusted networks, trusted hardware, leveraging enterprise directory infrastructure for authenticating its users to these applications are now running on un-trusted networks with other co-tenants of the same provider?
De-parameterization
Resource pooling

10-What five components broadly define IdEA?
Authentication
Authorization
Administration
Audit & Compliance
Policy

11-What is the the new emerging standard for Identity Management?
Simple Cloud Identity Management (SCIM) – uses well defined core schema, cloud friendly because it uses RESTful API, and supports identity management because it works with exisiting protocols such as SAML, OpenID connect

12-What threats does IdEA address in a cloud?
Spoofing – authentication ( strong authentication)
Tampering – Digital Signature or Hash (As used in SAML assertions)
Repudiation –Digital Signature (“”)
Information disclosure – SSL encryption
Denial of Service – Security Gateways (Web services security gateways
Elevation privilege – authorization (OAuth)

Match the Term with right definition
PDP				Policy Decision Point
PEP				Policy Enforcement Point
PAP				Policy Access Point
WS				Web Service
STS				Secure Token Service
WAM				Web Access Management
IdP				Identity Provider
IDM				Identity Management
SPML				Service Provisioning Mark-up Language
SCIM				Simple Cloud Identity Management
IAG				Identity and Access Governance 

 

Domain 11 Encryption and Key Management

1-What alternatives are there for organizations that have issues with sending unsecured data in the cloud?
Tokenization – where a public cloud service can be in integrated/paired with a private cloud that stores sensitive data
Data anonymization – Personally Identifiable information and Sensitive Personal information are stripped before processing
Utilizing cloud database controls – access controls built into the database are deemed to provide adequate levels of segregation
 

Domain 12 - Identity Entitlement and Access Management 

1-What’s the difference between a traditional IAM and a cloud architecture?
In a traditional IAM often all the components are stand-alone as part of a single server.
A cloud architecture is potentially more complex taking identity and attributes from a number of sources and making authorization / access management decisions via a set of entitlement rules defined by the entitlement process. 

2-What is federation?
Federation is the use of SAML to offer portability to disparate and independent security domains with some organizations extending their DS environment via a gateway product that will handle SAML assertions. 

3-What SPI model will use Federation widely?
SaaS deployment models as there are no similar standards for PaaS or IaaS deployment models. 


